<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blockchain on Keongtae Kim</title>
    <link>https://keongkim.github.io/tags/blockchain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blockchain on Keongtae Kim</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 02:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://keongkim.github.io/tags/blockchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics of NFT (Non-fungible Token)</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/nft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 02:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/nft/</guid>
      <description>Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs) witnessed a skyrocketing growth from a market cap of just $100m in 2020 to over $22bn in 2021, according to the data from DappRadar. Despite tremendous eyeballs on the rise and fall of this market, fundamental recognitions on the economic mechanisms behind this ecosystem are quite limited.
In this project, we aim to provide a thorough understanding of the dynamics in this rising market. Specifically, we plan to explore from three aspects, including trader and creator behaviors, and platform evolutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Regulations Affect Startup Locations: Evidence from Initial Coin Offerings</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/ico-regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 02:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/ico-regulation/</guid>
      <description>This study is an examination of initial coin offerings (ICOs), a new form of investment, using a fairly comprehensive dataset of 4,380 ICOs operating from 2017 to 2019. Specifically, we study whether ICO project creators’ decisions on remaining in or leaving the countries of origin are affected by the ICO policy status of countries. Findings indicate that countries having ICO regulations are more likely to both retain and attract ICO projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>