<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Keongtae Kim on Keongtae Kim</title>
    <link>https://keongkim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Keongtae Kim on Keongtae Kim</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How Regulations Affect Startup Locations: Evidence from Initial Coin Offerings</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/ico-regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 02:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/ico-regulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study is an examination of initial coin offerings (ICOs), a new form of investment, using a fairly comprehensive dataset of 4,380 ICOs operating from 2017 to 2019. Specifically, we study whether ICO project creators’ decisions on remaining in or leaving the countries of origin are affected by the ICO policy status of countries. Findings indicate that countries having ICO regulations are more likely to both retain and attract ICO projects. The effects are stronger for high-quality projects that value long-term stability than low-quality projects that may be fraudulent. The findings have implications for ICO regulators and startups by enhancing understandings of conditions that will retain and attract ICO projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IT Investments and Firm Risk Across Industries: Evidence from the Bond Market</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/risk-disclosure-in-crowdfunding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/risk-disclosure-in-crowdfunding/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IT Investments and Firm Risk Across Industries: Evidence from the Bond Market</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/software-innovation-and-product-differentiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/software-innovation-and-product-differentiation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equity Crowdfunding and Startup Performance</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/equity-crowdfunding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 02:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/equity-crowdfunding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study examines the effect of equity crowdfunding on startup performance. To do so, it uses a novel dataset of equity crowdfunding startups from January 2016 to April 2019 and constructs a sample of matched non-crowdfunding startups. The data indicate that equity crowdfunding startups rather than non-crowdfunding startups are more likely to survive, and conditional on closure, their closing dates are later than those of non-crowdfunding startups. Equity crowdfunding startups also show higher growth in employment. Additional analyses indicate that expert equity investors are crucial for startup performance at least by facilitating access to external funding and debt crowdfunding does not help startups increase performance significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Online Social Interactions Facilitate the Spatial Diffusion of Crowdfunding</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/spatioal-diffusion-crowdfunding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 02:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/spatioal-diffusion-crowdfunding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study documents the role of online social interactions in the diffusion of crowdfunding which has emerged as a viable alternative source of funding for creative projects and ventures around the world. Using the data on the creation of crowdfunding projects from a leading crowdfunding platform from 2009 to 2013 and Facebook Social Connectedness Index Data, we find that the number of crowdfunding projects initiated in an area is positively associated with the total number of prior crowdfunding projects from areas that are most socially connected online. The association is stronger when considering relatively large, successful projects. We also find that the peer effect from the socially connected areas becomes larger as the crowdfunding adoption from geographically proximate areas increases. Last, the influence of virtually connected areas is stronger for areas that are well off (i.e., areas with high internet coverage, education levels, technological capability, or entrepreneurial culture). The study provides new insights into the diffusion of crowdfunding and the digital divide, and has practical implications for platform providers and project creators.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Experts in the Crowd: The Role of Experienced Investors in a Crowdfunding Market</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/expertise-in-crowdfunding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/expertise-in-crowdfunding/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crowdfunding and the Democratization of Access to Capital: An Illusion? Evidence from Housing Prices</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/housing-prices-and-crowdfunding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/housing-prices-and-crowdfunding/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beauty, Gender, and Charitable Giving</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/beauty-crowdfunding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 05:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/beauty-crowdfunding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study examines the effect of physical attractiveness of recipients on donations decisions in a prosocial microlending market by combining both the archival data analysis and controlled experiments. We find that physical attractiveness of female recipients mattters to donors. More attractive recipients tend to have a larger share of male donors, implying that male (female) donors are more (less) favorable toward those recipients. On the contrary, the physical attractiveness of male recipients did not change the composition significantly. Our experiments show that this is partly because male donors give more to more attractive female recipients because of their intuitive preference, simply liking the attractive female more. These findings have implications for the beauty effect in crowd-driven platforms and provide guidance for recipients seeking donation from crowds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complements Rather Than Substitutes: An Empirical Examination of Cryptocurrency and Online Peer-to-Peer Lending Markets</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/cryptocurrency-p2plending/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 02:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/cryptocurrency-p2plending/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We study the effect of cryptocurrency markets on borrowers in peer-to-peer (P2P) lending markets. By using the combined data from both markets during the period January 2017 to February 2018, we provide several novel findings. Our results indicate that the growth in cryptocurrency markets is associated with a large amount of loan requests in the P2P market. This complementarity is strong for borrowers who have good credit grades and are likely to have further knowledge of and might use the borrowed money for investing in the cryptocurrency market. The growth in cryptocurrency markets is further associated with a low default rate, a low interest rate, a high full-funded probability, and a short time required to meet the borrowing goal. These findings are also confirmed by our additional tests using exogenous natural shocks with propensity score matching. Overall, our study highlights the potential of the P2P lending market as a funding source for investment in the cryptocurrency market, especially for high-creditworthy investors who likely have a low entering cost into the cryptocurrency market. Implications for both cryptocurrencies and P2P markets are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Crowdfunding Success on Subsequent Financing Outcomes of Start-ups</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/crowdfunding-vc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:20:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/crowdfunding-vc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IT Investments and Firm Risk Across Industries: Evidence from the Bond Market</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/it-bond-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/it-bond-market/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Product Market Competition Drive CVC Investment? Evidence from the U.S. IT Industry</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/corporate-venture-capital/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/corporate-venture-capital/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industry-Specific Human Capital and Wages: Evidence from the Business Process Outsourcing Industry</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/human-capital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/human-capital/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;How Online Social Interactions Affect the Spatial Diffusion of Crowdfunding&#39; and 1 other paper</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/talk/informs-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/talk/informs-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Soft but Strong: Software-Based Innovation, Product Market Competition, and Value Creation in the IT Hardware Inudstry&#39; and 1 other paper</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/talk/aom-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/talk/aom-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
