<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Keongtae Kim on Keongtae Kim</title>
    <link>https://keongkim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Keongtae Kim on Keongtae Kim</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdependence between online peer‐to‐peer lending and cryptocurrency markets and its effects on financial inclusion</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/cryptocurrency-p2plending/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/cryptocurrency-p2plending/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Crowdfunding Success on Subsequent Financing Outcomes of Start-ups</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/crowdfunding-vc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/crowdfunding-vc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk Disclosure in Crowdfunding</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/risk-disclosure-in-crowdfunding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/risk-disclosure-in-crowdfunding/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics of NFT (Non-fungible Token)</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/nft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 02:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/nft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs) witnessed a skyrocketing growth from a market cap of just $100m in 2020 to over $22bn in 2021, according to the data from DappRadar. Despite tremendous eyeballs on the rise and fall of this market, fundamental recognitions on the economic mechanisms behind this ecosystem are quite limited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, we aim to provide a thorough understanding of the dynamics in this rising market. Specifically, we plan to explore from three aspects, including trader and creator behaviors, and platform evolutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the most crucial players in this market, traders, including sellers and buyers, exhibit large differences in their behaviors such as tastes for items, bidding strategies, and operation frequencies. What drives the tastes and corresponding demands? The feature of sole uniqueness, or embedded higher-level utility, or even those stories upon which assets are built such as creations or preceding owners? Whether and how do traders react to different models, such as fixed-price or auction sales, single-piece or bundle sales, in this highly differentiated market? Aggregately speaking, are there crowd behaviors, either rational or irrational, that are salient enough to affect decisions? Overall, answers to these questions can help make sense of who sustain the growth of NFT markets, and more importantly, how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creators, the major contributors of these flourishing NFT assets, serve a vital role in this two-sided market. Being able to profit from both initial sales and royalties from following resales, creators are now facing an entirely different incentive structure than traditional counterpart. Why do creators formulate contracts in different ways such as price, royalty percentage, or total number of owners? How do creators balance the effort tradeoff between quantity and quality? Answers to these questions are of value not only for NFT market, but also for long-lasting economic discussions on market structure and incentive design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, as an open market, NFT platforms are characterized by interoperability and tradability, suggesting network effect could potentially make much greater impact on the evolution of NFT market than on social media ten years ago. Therefore, understanding the dynamics of network and community structure within NFT market can be both exciting and meaningful. For example, which type of network, random or clustered, can diffuse information quicker? Similar questions could have real practical implications on user cultivation, advertising campaign, and even platform interface designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overviewing these heated discussions, some argue that NFTs are only symptomatic of an unsustainable, digital gold rush. Others firmly support for its unprecedented game-changing power in multiple respects of the future. In light of the pandemic accidentally bringing everything online (lectures, conferences, even social gatherings), we are confident as well as looking forward to this new world. We hope our research can probe into the underlying mechanic functions and help pave the way for an even clearer and brighter future of cryptocurrency system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft but Strong: Software-Based Innovation and Product Differentiation in the IT Hardware Industry</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/software-innovation-and-product-differentiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/software-innovation-and-product-differentiation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Piracy of Live Content and Online Illegal Gambling: Evidence from Live Sports Broadcasting</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/digital-piracy-illegal-gambling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 02:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/digital-piracy-illegal-gambling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When digital content that was once freely available through public (or free) distribution channels becomes unavailable, users are often compelled to resort to illegal channels for pirating the content. In many cases, these illegal content distributors generate profits by affiliating with illicit partners such as illegal gambling sites, while offering the content to users for free. This practice is particularly prevalent in live sports broadcasting markets. As such, this research seeks to investigate how digital piracy of live sports content is associated with illicit gambling activities. In September 2020, a leading media company in South Korea ceased selling the license of English Football League (EPL) broadcasting to popular media outlets that previously offered the content for free and started charging subscription fees for the content views. Using this event as an exogenous shock (i.e., treatment event), we analyze the causal relationship between digital piracy and illegal gambling activities. The study finds that the more individuals visited the illegal sports broadcasting website, the more likely they were to engage in illicit gambling activities. The main research findings make significant contributions to our understanding of the digital piracy of live content and its potential societal consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Live Shopping on Sellers on an E-commerce Platform</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/livestreaming-online-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 02:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/livestreaming-online-sales/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The widespread adoption of live shopping on e-commerce platforms has created opportunities for sellers to reach broader audiences and increase sales. Using a comprehensive dataset of sellers’ live shopping practices, this study examines the effect of live shopping on sellers in two major product categories on Korea’s largest e-commerce platform. Our findings indicate a positive impact on sales for broadcasting sellers during livestreaming events. In addition, we find significant temporal changes in sales even before and after livestreaming dates. Our findings suggest that live shopping acts as an informational discovery channel that helps attract and retain customer attention. Furthermore, we investigate the aggregate impact on platform growth and find that livestreams have a positive effect not only on livestreaming sellers but also on non-streaming stores, contributing to sustainable platform growth. These findings underscore the potential of live shopping as an effective tool to influence sales on e-commerce platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Location-Based Recommendation Systems and Local Economy</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/smart-around/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 02:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/smart-around/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Bike-Sharing Services on Local Business</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/bike-sharing-restaurant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 02:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/bike-sharing-restaurant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the significance of bike-sharing services as a daily means of transportation and their potential to influence supply and demand in the local economy, the impact of these services on local businesses has not been studied yet. Hence, this research aims to examine how a bike sharing program influences the success of local businesses. We analyzed data on 3,623 local restaurants and their credit card sales recorded from February to August 2019, along with bike rentals made by local passengers near the restaurants, to investigate the association between bike-sharing rentals and local restaurant sales. Our findings show that the number of bike rentals around a restaurant is positively associated with its sales. We further find that the impact of bike rentals becomes more significant when there are more subway passengers around the restaurants, while the impact becomes less significant when there are more bus passengers. This indicates that consumers use bikes as a last-mile transit mode for restaurant visits. Moreover, we find that non-franchise (less-popular) and new restaurants (opened within 1-year) benefit more from the bike-sharing program. We believe that the main findings offer significant contributions to existing literature by theorizing the value of sharing economy programs in the local economy context. In addition, our results provide strategic implications for policymakers and local businesses to make effective use of sharing economy programs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Regulations Affect Startup Locations: Evidence from Initial Coin Offerings</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/ico-regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 02:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/ico-regulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study is an examination of initial coin offerings (ICOs), a new form of investment, using a fairly comprehensive dataset of 4,380 ICOs operating from 2017 to 2019. Specifically, we study whether ICO project creators’ decisions on remaining in or leaving the countries of origin are affected by the ICO policy status of countries. Findings indicate that countries having ICO regulations are more likely to both retain and attract ICO projects. The effects are stronger for high-quality projects that value long-term stability than low-quality projects that may be fraudulent. The findings have implications for ICO regulators and startups by enhancing understandings of conditions that will retain and attract ICO projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Makes the Magic Happen? Investigating the Effectiveness of Promotion Strategies</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/promotion-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 02:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/promotion-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Online platforms have emerged as an alternative method for companies to directly introduce and promote their products to their target audience, bypassing the need for third-party endorsements. However, the effectiveness of self-promotion compared to external promotion remains uncertain. This study utilizes role theory and focuses on a specialized online community platform for technological products to examine the impact of external promoters versus internal promoters. Our findings reveal that external promoters are more effective in promoting products, as they receive a higher number of upvotes from platform supporters compared to internal promoters. Additionally, the effectiveness of external promoters is enhanced when they promote a larger quantity of products. Furthermore, the concurrent promotion of additional products influences the effectiveness of a focal product&amp;rsquo;s promotion in a complex manner, revealing the intricacies of promotional practices in the dynamic context of new product introductions. Overall, our research underscores the significance of individuals maintaining their primary roles to avoid role conflict and enhance effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equity Crowdfunding and Startup Performance</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/equity-crowdfunding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 02:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/equity-crowdfunding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study examines the effect of equity crowdfunding on startup performance. To do so, it uses a novel dataset of equity crowdfunding startups from January 2016 to April 2019 and constructs a sample of matched non-crowdfunding startups. The data indicate that equity crowdfunding startups rather than non-crowdfunding startups are more likely to survive, and conditional on closure, their closing dates are later than those of non-crowdfunding startups. Equity crowdfunding startups also show higher growth in employment. Additional analyses indicate that expert equity investors are crucial for startup performance at least by facilitating access to external funding and debt crowdfunding does not help startups increase performance significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Machine-Generated Ratings and Social Exposure Affect Human Reviewers: Evidence from Initial Coin Offerings</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/machine-human-rating-ico/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 02:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/machine-human-rating-ico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While machine-generated information has become more prevalent in online professional ratings, how it is used as a basis for human ratings has been relatively underexplored. Using online professional ratings of initial coin offerings (ICOs) projects as a context, this study examines how the increased social exposure of human ratings and the different types of experiences influence the ratings of human ICO experts relative to machine-generated ratings. Leveraging an event of an interface design change on a major ICO rating platform, we find that the increased social exposure of human ratings makes human experts with advisor experiences reduce their rating levels, makes them less likely to rate above the machine-generated rating scores, and makes them rate closer to the machine-generated rating scores. We also find that the increased social exposure of human ratings makes human experts with team member experiences (of ICO projects) rate closer to the machine-generated rating scores, although the increased social exposure does not significantly change their rating levels. Our findings suggest that human experts with advisor experiences may strategically go above the machine-generated scores to overrate projects and impress the project teams, while human experts with team member experiences do not have the tendency to overrate. In general, the increased social exposure drives human experts to conform to the machine-generated scores in ratings and possibly corrects the biases in human ratings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Online Social Interactions Facilitate the Spatial Diffusion of Crowdfunding</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/project/spatioal-diffusion-crowdfunding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 02:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/project/spatioal-diffusion-crowdfunding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study documents the role of online social interactions in the diffusion of crowdfunding which has emerged as a viable alternative source of funding for creative projects and ventures around the world. Using the data on the creation of crowdfunding projects from a leading crowdfunding platform from 2009 to 2013 and Facebook Social Connectedness Index Data, we find that the number of crowdfunding projects initiated in an area is positively associated with the total number of prior crowdfunding projects from areas that are most socially connected online. The association is stronger when considering relatively large, successful projects. We also find that the peer effect from the socially connected areas becomes larger as the crowdfunding adoption from geographically proximate areas increases. Last, the influence of virtually connected areas is stronger for areas that are well off (i.e., areas with high internet coverage, education levels, technological capability, or entrepreneurial culture). The study provides new insights into the diffusion of crowdfunding and the digital divide, and has practical implications for platform providers and project creators.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Experts in the Crowd: The Role of Experienced Investors in a Crowdfunding Market</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/expertise-in-crowdfunding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/publication/expertise-in-crowdfunding/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
