<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Keongtae Kim</title>
    <link>https://keongkim.github.io/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Keongtae Kim</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://keongkim.github.io/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Biography Prof. Keongtae Kim is an Associate Professor in Department of Decisions, Operations and Technology, The Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK) Business School. Prior to joining CUHK, he was an Assistant Professor at Department of Information Systems at the City University of Hong Kong. He earned his PhD in Information Systems from the Robert H. Smith School of Business at the University of Maryland. His main research focuses on economics of information and technology, digital innovation/entrepreneurship, FinTech and economics of AI/ML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Publications</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/home/publications_selected/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/home/publications_selected/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/home/publications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working Paper</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Teaching Interests  Business Analytics and Intelligence, Platform Strategy, Fintech and Blockchain, Digital Innovation and Entrepreneurship  Teaching Experience CUHK Business School, Chinese University of Hong Kong
 Blockchain and its Business Application (A graduate course to teach blockchain and its use cases) Business Intelligence Techniques and Applications II (A graduate course to teach advanced predictive analytics using Python) Business Intelligence Techniques and Applications I (A graduate course to teach basic predictive analytics using Python) Business Analytics (An undergraduate course to teach basic predictive analytics using Python) Business Information Systems (An undergraduate course to teach the introduction to information systems including data analysis using RapidMiner)  College of Business, City University of Hong Kong</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://keongkim.github.io/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keongkim.github.io/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>